<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-12-12T20:32:04+01:00</updated><id>https://dbzxexpert.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Morocco, a booming electric cars market and soon an autonomous vehicules hotspot!</title><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2022/Morocco,-a-booming-electric-cars-market-and-soon-an-autonomous-vehiculs-hotspot!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Morocco, a booming electric cars market and soon an autonomous vehicules hotspot!"/><published>2022-08-29T16:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-08-29T16:01:00+01:00</updated><id>https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2022/Morocco,%20a%20booming%20electric%20cars%20market%20and%20soon%20an%20autonomous%20vehiculs%20hotspot!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2022/Morocco,-a-booming-electric-cars-market-and-soon-an-autonomous-vehiculs-hotspot!/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="jun-23-1740---the-future-of-autonomous-vehicules-in-africa">Jun 23, 17:40 - The future of autonomous vehicules in Africa</h2> <h3 id="overview">Overview</h3> <p>In fact, the country is establishing itself as a prominent participant in the electric car industry. Morocco already has a yearly production capability of 40,000 electric vehicles. According to the Moroccan Minister of Trade and Industry, the goal is to raise this to 100,000 by 2025.</p> <p>Morocco is now a vibrant player in the automobile sector. It possesses a lot of advantages that are favorable to success in this industry.</p> <h3 id="future-is-promising">Future is promising</h3> <p>For starters, its excellent geographic location allows it to conveniently service European markets.</p> <p>Furthermore, this North African country has significant renewable energy potential. As a result, it can generate <strong>low-cost power</strong> for electric vehicles. Morocco has a significant edge in wind and solar power generation due to its outstanding sunlight and exposure to strong, consistent winds. This allows it to diversify its energy sources and lessen its reliance on fossil fuels.</p> <p>Morocco’s automobile industry employs around 230,000 people, with a <strong>trained workforce</strong>. This workforce consists of highly skilled technicians, engineers, and workers. They have acquired extensive training and manufacture high-quality automobiles. The country intends to train even more specialists. The goal is to increase its desire to become a major participant in the electric vehicle market. Automotive schools and firms give appropriate training in robotics, electronics, information technology, and quality management. By investing in coaching and training in this manner, Morocco increases its attractiveness to international investors while also assisting in the creation of skilled employment in the country.</p> <p>Atlas E-Mobility will launch <strong>the very first electric car manufactured in Africa</strong>, with the ambition of competing with Tesla in the market.</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/YG4GdqgY"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/KzfPv18q/image.png" alt="Crédit photo : Istockphotos"/></a> Crédit photo : Istockphotos</p> <p>The introduction of self-driving cars in Morocco has the potential to transform the transportation environment and provide significant benefits to the country. These cars can improve road safety by reducing human mistake, reducing traffic congestion, and optimizing fuel efficiency. Furthermore, the adoption of self-driving vehicles might increase accessibility and transportation, particularly in distant or disadvantaged regions, boosting economic growth and linking communities. Adoption of this cutting-edge technology has the potential to establish Morocco as a regional leader in smart mobility, attracting investment and encouraging long-term urban development.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="day-to-day"/><category term="News,"/><category term="Autonomous"/><category term="cars,"/><category term="Morocco"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jun 23, 17:40 - The future of autonomous vehicules in Africa]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The correct mindset</title><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2021/correct-mindset/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The correct mindset"/><published>2021-03-02T20:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-02T20:01:00+01:00</updated><id>https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2021/correct-mindset</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2021/correct-mindset/"><![CDATA[<p>So it’s another day, maybe a Monday or, God forbid, the beginning of a new month. And, <strong>oh my</strong>, it’s time to make those new resolutions that I always abandon at the first sign of inconvenience. ence.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm-12 offset-sm-1 mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/resolution.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> <a href="https://xkcd.com/1154/"> xkcd: Resolution</a> </div> <p>I feel the problem here is faulty mental conditioning. Expecting someone to “go there and <strong>do it</strong>” is unrealistic. “Doing it” needs a number of factors to work smoothly. Things that are sometimes beyond my control. For example, I may try to start writing a blog <em>this</em> Monday but be unable to do so due to an important job at work that I had to do after office hours. That is how life is. It’s difficult.</p> <p>So, instead, I think in a different way: Accept that I will <em>inevitably</em> encounter huge challenges in the future. For example, before committing to a new resolve, I like to squeeze skin on my arm to experience some discomfort. That way, I convince the lazy portion of my brain, “Yes, it will hurt.” Yes, I will continue to feel agony. Yes, I will keep this resolution no matter what.” More significantly, I picture how, despite my best efforts, I <em>fail</em> to attain whatever goal I had in mind. This, I feel, is particularly significant, since with long-term resolves, there will <em>inevitably</em> be times when I will be convinced that “it’s hopeless, I can’t do it.”. “I failed.” However, in long-term commitments, these brief moments of desperation should not decide the direction of action. It takes more time to ensure that I did, in fact, fail. And acting on such an inclination is just not healthy.</p> <p>Some may argue that this approach is synonymous with “having low expectations to be happier in the end.” Having high expectations, on the other hand, inspires me more, despite what I wrote above.</p> <p>So, if I were to condense everything above in a single line, it would be something like “Pain <em>and</em> Gain.” In addition, there is a film with the same name and concept <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1980209/">that exact name</a>, check it out, it’s great. :smile:</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="day-to-day"/><category term="mindset,"/><category term="sision,"/><category term="motivation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How I retain my sanity while working in AI]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Customize your learning as a data scientist</title><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/Customize-your-learning-as-a-data-scientist/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Customize your learning as a data scientist"/><published>2020-10-02T20:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-02T20:01:00+01:00</updated><id>https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/Customize-your-learning-as-a-data-scientist</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/Customize-your-learning-as-a-data-scientist/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://postimg.cc/RNswBrPs"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/2SmGnrnD/image.png" alt="image.png"/></a></p> <p>Have you ever got the idea for an awesome data science project, looked up the data you’ll need online, but it’s nowhere to be found? Unfortunately, not every dataset you’ll ever require is available online. So, what are your options? Should you abandon your concept and return to Kaggle? No! A true data scientist should be able to gather his or her own DATA!</p> <h1 id="whats-web-scraping-and-why-learn-it">What’s Web Scraping and why learn it?</h1> <p>The internet is the single most important source of data; it is a virtual record of human knowledge, at least for the last 20 years. Web scraping is the skill of obtaining data from the internet as a Data Scientist. It’s a fantastic tool that offers up so many possibilities for unique projects.</p> <p><strong>Please be in mind that certain websites forbid scraping and may block your IP address if you scrape too frequently or maliciously..</strong></p> <h1 id="how-do-we-scrape"><strong>How do we scrape?</strong></h1> <p>There are two approaches when it comes to web scraping.</p> <p><strong>Request-based scraping</strong>: With this method, we will submit a request to the website’s server, which will return the HTML of the page, which is the same content that you see when you click “View page source” in Google Chrome, which you can try right now by clicking <strong>ctrl+u</strong>.Then, normally, we will use a library to parse the HTML and retrieve the desired data. This approach is simple, lightweight, and very fast; however, it is not perfect, and there is one disadvantage that may deter you from using it; in fact, most modern websites nowadays use JavaScript to render their content, IE: you don’t see the content of the page until the JavaScript executes, which the request method cannot handle.</p> <p><strong>Request-based scraping</strong>: In this strategy, we will submit a request to the website’s server, which will return the HTML of the page, which is the same content that you see when you click “View page source” in Google Chrome, which you can try right now by clicking <strong>ctrl+u</strong>.Then we normally use a library to parse the HTML and extract the desired data. This approach is simple, lightweight, and very fast; however, it is not perfect, and there is one drawback that may deter you from using it; in fact, most modern websites nowadays use JavaScript to render their content, IE: you don’t see the content of the page until after the JavaScript executes, which the request method cannot handle.</p> <h1 id="scrape-using-selenium">Scrape using selenium:</h1> <p>Selenium is a popular web automation framework, but it can also be used for scraping! You can basically imitate any operation that a human can do manually using selenium. You may construct a bot that will take particular actions when something happens, or you can make selenium scan web sites and scrape data for you, which is what we’ll be doing in this tutorial.</p> <p>To parse the HTML we will be using beautiful soup.</p> <p>Here are documentation links for further reading. <a href="https://selenium-python.readthedocs.io/">selenium</a> and <a href="https://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/bs4/doc/">beautiful soup</a></p> <h1 id="demo-scraping-jobs-from-indeeds-job-board">Demo: Scraping Jobs from Indeed’s Job board</h1> <p>Let’s get started; the purpose of this example is to scrape jobs from Indeed based on a search query and store them in a csv file.</p> <p>More precisely we are interested in:</p> <ul> <li>Job title</li> <li>Location of the job</li> <li>Company that posted the offer</li> <li>Job description</li> <li>When the job was posted</li> </ul> <p>First let’s import the libraries that we’il work with:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>from bs4 import BeautifulSoup  
from webdriver_manager.chrome import ChromeDriverManager  
import pandas as pd  
from selenium import webdriver  
from selenium.webdriver.chrome.options import Options
chrome_options = Options()  
chrome_options.add_argument("--headless")
</code></pre></div></div> <ul> <li>Beautiful Soup is used to interface with HTML</li> <li>Pandas is used to output to csv</li> <li>The web driver is the real browser; we will use Chrome and configure it to run in <strong>headless mode</strong>, which means it will run in the background and we will not be able to see a browser scrolling through the job sites; if you want to view the browser, you may delete it!</li> </ul> <p>The first step is to obtain the real job pages; fortunately, Lucky offers a search option; simply browse to:</p> <p>“https://fr.indeed.com/jobs?q=data+scientist&amp;start=10”</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/62pY0VTT"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/B6xkJM05/image.png" alt="image.png"/></a></p> <p>You’ll be sent to the second page of data science jobs, where you may modify the search query by changing the <strong>q</strong> argument and the page number by changing the <strong>start</strong> argument. I’m using the Indeed Moroccan portal, but this will work in any nation.</p> <p>Two functions will be implemented. One is a helper method for navigating to a URL, extracting the HTML and converting it to a Beautiful Soup object with which we can interact, while the other extracts links to job pages:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>def toSoup(url):  
    driver.get(url)  
    html = driver.page_source  
    soup = BeautifulSoup(html, 'lxml')  
    return soupdef getPageUrls(query,number):  
    url="[https://fr.indeed.com/emplois?q=](https:/fr.indeed.com/emplois?q=)"+str(query)+"&amp;start="+str(((number-1)\*10))  
    soup=toSoup(url)  
    maxPages=soup.find("div",{"id":"searchCountPages"}).text.strip().split(" ")[3]  
    return maxPages,[appendIndeedUrl(a["href"]) for a in soup.findAll("a",{"class":"jobtitle turnstileLink"})]
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Now that we have the URLs, let’s put them to use to extract what we want from the job page:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>def paragraphArrayToSingleString(paragraphs):  
    string=""  
    for paragraph in paragraphs:  
        string=string+"\\n"+paragraph.text.strip()  
    return stringdef appendIndeedUrl(url):  
    return "[https://fr.indeed.com](https://fr.indeed.com)"+str(url)def processPage(url):  
    soup=toSoup(url)  
    title=soup.find("h1",{"class":"icl-u-xs-mb--xs icl-u-xs-mt--none jobsearch-JobInfoHeader-title"}).text.strip()  
    CompanyAndLocation=soup.find("div",{"class":"jobsearch-InlineCompanyRating icl-u-xs-mt--xs jobsearch-DesktopStickyContainer-companyrating"})  
    length=len(CompanyAndLocation)  
    if length==3:  
        company=CompanyAndLocation.findAll("div")[0].text.strip()  
        location=CompanyAndLocation.findAll("div")[2].text.strip()  
    else:  
        company="NAN"  
        location=CompanyAndLocation.findAll("div")[0].text.strip()  
    date=soup.find("div",{"class":"jobsearch-JobMetadataFooter"}).text.split("-")[1].strip()  
    description=paragraphArrayToSingleString(soup.find("div",{"id":"jobDescriptionText"}).findAll())  
    return {"title":title,"company":company,"location":location,"date":date,"description":description}def getMaxPages(query):  
    url="[https://fr.indeed.com/emplois?q=](https://fr.indeed.com/emplois?q=)"+str(query)
</code></pre></div></div> <p>We’re utilizing HTML characteristics like “class” and “id” to get the information we’re looking for; you can figure out how to choose the data you need by studying the website.</p> <p>Here’s an illustration of the title property:</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/nXkDFyc9"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/BvWcg3rp/image.png" alt="image.png"/></a></p> <p>The title is a “h1” that we may pick by utilizing its class.</p> <p>Finally, let’s write a function that will loop over all of the jobs and store them to a csv file.</p> <p>Take note that we are getting the maximum amount of pages so that the crawler will stop when we reach the last page.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>def getJobsForQuery(query):  
    data=[]  
    maxPages=999  
    for number in range(maxPages):  
        maxPages,urls=getPageUrls(query,number+1)  
        for url in urls:  
            try:  
                page=processPage(url)  
                data.append(page)  
            except:  
                pass  
        print("finished Page number: "+str(number+1))  
    #Save the data to a csv file  
    pd.DataFrame(data).to_csv("jobs_"+query+".csv")
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Now let’s scrape some data scientist offers:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>driver = webdriver.Chrome(ChromeDriverManager().install(),options=chrome_options)  
getJobsForQuery("data scientist")
</code></pre></div></div> <p>What we got:</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/WD5YkYSh"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/hjBkNHdb/image.png" alt="image.png"/></a> A Sample of scraped jobs</p> <h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1> <p>In this post, we learnt about web scraping, why it’s crucial for every aspiring data scientist, and the many techniques of extracting jobs from Indeed.</p> <p>if you made it this far Congratulations. Thank you for reading, and I hope you found the material interesting. Feel free to contact me on social media for personal contact or conversation.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="day-to-day"/><category term="scraping,"/><category term="data"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This single skill will open a whole world of new possibilities for you]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Humanitarian aid amidst the COVID-19 pandemic</title><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/Corona-aid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Humanitarian aid amidst the COVID-19 pandemic"/><published>2020-06-29T16:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-29T16:01:00+01:00</updated><id>https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/Corona-aid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/Corona-aid/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="social-work-and-volunteering">Social work and volunteering</h2> <p>Engaging in humanitarian aid efforts has been an immensely rewarding and heartening experience, as my team and I had the privilege to extend a helping hand to <strong>over 50 local families</strong> grappling with the socio-economic fallout of the <strong>coronavirus pandemic</strong>. Witnessing the profound impact of our assistance on these families, who faced unforeseen challenges, filled us with gratitude and happiness. The opportunity to provide not only essential supplies but also a sense of solidarity and support during these trying times reinforced our belief in the strength of community and compassion.</p> <p>In addition to the material aid, we recognized the pressing need to address the educational disruptions caused by the pandemic. Acknowledging the struggles faced by students adapting to remote learning, our team extended its efforts to provide educational support in science subjects for the children within these families. By offering tutoring and resources, we aimed to bridge the educational gap and empower the youth with knowledge and skills to navigate the challenges of remote study. This holistic approach to humanitarian aid reflects our commitment to uplifting communities in times of crisis and nurturing the future generations with the tools they need to overcome adversity. The experience has been deeply fulfilling, affirming the profound impact that collective acts of kindness can have on the lives of those facing adversity.</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/GHNSw6zt"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/9QF3Th7d/image.png" alt="image.png"/></a></p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/nMKDtmkD"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/c12MwMtX/Volunteering-1.jpg" alt="Volunteering-1.jpg"/></a>v</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/nXBp94PF"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/Cx61tJCq/ANNEXE-4-page-0001.jpg" alt="ANNEXE-4-page-0001.jpg"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="day-to-day"/><category term="Volunteering,"/><category term="Aid,"/><category term="Covid"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social work and volunteering]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ECC innovation hackathon</title><link href="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/ECC-innovation-hackathon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ECC innovation hackathon"/><published>2020-02-07T16:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-07T16:01:00+01:00</updated><id>https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/ECC%20innovation%20hackathon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dbzxexpert.github.io/blog/2020/ECC-innovation-hackathon/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="feb-07-1740---yassir">Feb 07, 17:40 - Yassir</h2> <h3 id="overview">Overview</h3> <h5 id="the-key-to-the-journey-to-mars-the-ion-engine"><strong>The key to the journey to Mars: the ion engine</strong></h5> <p>Exploring the vast wonders of space has always fascinated me, igniting a deep curiosity about the technologies that enable us to traverse the cosmic distances between celestial bodies. In the realm of propulsion systems, one innovation that particularly captivates me is the advent of ion engines. These electrostatically propelled marvels represent a paradigm shift from traditional chemical rockets, offering unparalleled efficiency and the potential for extended space missions. Having delved into this captivating field, I recently had the opportunity</p> <p>to contribute to a project centered around the application of ion engines for deep-space exploration. Drawing inspiration from the success of missions like NASA’s Dawn spacecraft, which harnessed the power of ion propulsion to explore asteroids Vesta and Ceres, our project aimed to further unlock the capabilities of these engines for ambitious missions into the far reaches of our solar system.</p> <p>As we delved into the intricacies of ion propulsion, a significant aspect that emerged was the critical role of propellant selection. The choice of ionic gases, with xenon being a prevalent but scarce option, introduced a fascinating challenge. This led our team to explore innovative solutions for sustainable and efficient propellants, acknowledging the need for a strategic approach to ensure the continued advancement of ion engines.</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/LqnnmrZD"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/wBkJQzqC/az.png" alt="az.png"/></a></p> <p>Ion engines prove to be the superior option for long space journeys that require substantial fuel reserves. Unlike traditional chemical propulsion systems, ion engines offer exceptional efficiency, making them ideal for missions requiring continuous, low-thrust propulsion. Their ability to gradually increase a spacecraft’s velocity over an extended duration makes them a preferred choice for interplanetary exploration and beyond. Additionally, these engines emerge as the superior solution for space study missions, such as transporting space telescopes, as well as for conveying consumables and spare parts to distant destinations. Their high efficiency and capability to maintain a steady thrust position them as essential tools for the execution of complex missions demanding increased endurance and optimal utilization of available resources.</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/yW93g4pr"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/BZ7TzJTs/az2.png" alt="az2.png"/></a></p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/Q9F5nFbX"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/C1NN5Dnf/az3.png" alt="az3.png"/></a></p> <p>In the recent hackathon, my team and I undertook an ambitious project aimed at developing a do-it-yourself (DIY) simulation of an ion engine, utilizing readily available materials. We were fortunate to have access to a vacuum chamber, which allowed us to conduct a series of comprehensive tests using various gases, including Xe, Ar, I2, He, and others. Our approach was rooted in a meticulous consideration of crucial properties such as molecular mass and ionization energy, which directly influence the propulsion force achievable with each gas. By experimenting with different gases, we sought to understand their impact on the density of propellants and, consequently, gauge the potential fuel efficiency achievable for space missions.</p> <p>What set our project apart was the holistic evaluation of factors beyond mere performance metrics. We delved into considerations of cost-effectiveness, safety, and health factors associated with each gas. This comprehensive analysis aimed to identify propellants that not only optimized propulsion but also met the stringent criteria necessary for space travel. Through this hackathon endeavor, we not only simulated ion engine dynamics but also embarked on a journey to strategically assess and select the most suitable propellants for future space missions, keeping in mind the multifaceted challenges and demands of deep space exploration.</p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/YvSSxJ87"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/x1vb9QzX/az4.jpg" alt="az4.jpg"/></a></p> <p><a href="https://postimg.cc/5XjCtHh8"><img src="https://i.postimg.cc/y8yXvcnp/az5.jpg" alt="az5.jpg"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="day-to-day"/><category term="hackathon,"/><category term="Ionic"/><category term="motors,"/><category term="innovation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Documenting my participation to the ECC innovation hackathon]]></summary></entry></feed>